l'M Chef Mahjoub Khalifa Aouidet (Alias Evan Carlo)



"Good food ends with good talk."

Mahjoub Khalifa





evan.carlo1



evan.carlo



evan carlo



Chef Mahjoub Khalifa Aouidet

Executive Head Master Chef / Food & Beverages Consultant

General Vice President Global World Association of Master Chefs (WAMC)

Dammam, As Shati, Saudi Arabia

Tell: 00966-544798792 / 00966-554903591

Email: carlonat38@ gmail.com carlowamc1950@gmail.com Karfaguen1966@gmail.com



Iob Objective

Energetic executive head chef with 30+ years' Bringing a strong background in ensuring high culinary and foodservice standards in busy kitchens, along with a great ability to handle kitchen budgets in a profound manner. experience in all aspects of restaurant & cafe and operations management within the hospitality industry. Exceptional interpersonal skills combined with proven ability to drive profitability manage and nurture talent deliver sales growth form strategic partnerships and successfully implement challenging projects. Outstanding leader with distinguished team-building skills and excellent conflict resolution abilities as well as a strong work ethic and great sense of humor.

Skills

- Fluent in Arabic, English, Russian, Italian & French.
- **Exceptional breadth of food industry experience.**
- Great cooking skills and attention to detail
- Leadership and management skills
- ❖ The ability to manage a budget and keep accurate records
- Good organisation and communication skills
- The ability to work under pressure
- The ability to inspire others and help them develop
- Innovation in your cooking; customers want to see something different
- Excellent communication skills.
- ❖ Physically fit to work on a shifting schedule.
- ❖ Able to work under pressure and achieve deadlines.
- Great cooking skills and attention to detail
- ❖ Willingness to Learn.
- Becoming a chef can be a hands-on learning experience, and like they say, practice does make perfect.
- Genuine Passion.
- Organisation.
- Ability to Skilfully Multitask.
- Creativity.
- Time Management.
- . Teamwork.

Core Qualifications

- Menu planning.
- Ensuring food is priced right.
- ❖ Making sure the quality of the food is in keeping with the calibre of restaurant you're serving it from.
- Managing stock and ordering food from various suppliers.
- Controlling and managing a budget.
- Maintaining good health and hygiene standards.
- Organising the staff rota and ensuring everyone knows what they're doing.
- * Recruiting new staff and training and developing existing team members.
- Strong education and hands-on experience in the preparation and management of meals and menus
- Solid understanding of how to adjust taste and ingredients to accommodate a variety of tongues diets cultures etc.
- Exceptional communication skills for giving instructions and training staff in the best ways to design and cook present foods
- Creative and innovative with presentation of foods for guests
- Organized utilizing the best ways to save costs and manage time whether preparing simple short orders or complicated dishes

Professional Experience

Executive Head Chef
 Buonasera Italian High-end Fine Dining Restaurant
 Dammam, Saudi Arabia. (Currently Working)

***** 2018

Grand Elysee (Consulting)
Aero Food Moldova (Consulting)

- ❖ 2010-2019, Executive Chef Infoton-com SRL, Kishinev, Moldova
- 2009-2010 Head Chef5 Star Diplomat Hotel, Moldova
- 2006-2009, Executive Chef Kitchen
 Le Saloon, Restaurant Gastronomy, Sousse
- 2004-2006 Kitchen Chef Hotel Tej Marhaba Tunisia, 5 stars, Sousse
- **❖** 2003-2004 Senior Chef STE. LA CAMPAGNE
- 2001-2003 Chef Italian Cuisine Specialty
 Miramar Hotels Carthage Palace, 5 stars, Gammarth, Tunis

❖ 2000-2001 Junior Chef Corinthian Khams Hotel Tunisia, 5 stars

Responsibilities & Knowledge:

- Prepared menus for corporate events weddings birthday parties and other occasions at the resort
- Delegated and supervised responsibilities of trainees
- ❖ Managed careful practices of raw material safe food handling procedures and cost
- Ensured appropriate and regulated execution of recipes
- Collaborated with accounting and management to manage finances and inventory
- ❖ Determined ambience of restaurant that worked with menu
- Interviewed hired and oversaw training of serving crew
- Supervised and mentored staff responsible for short orders
- Inspected deliveries for freshness and monitored proper storage per local food handling codes
- ❖ Interacted frequently with guests to enhance their meal experience
- ❖ Maintaining and improving the company's existing Quality Management System.
- Coordinating daily restaurant management operations.
- ❖ Delivering superior food and beverage service and maximizing customer satisfaction.
- Organize and supervise shifts.
- **Section** Estimate future needs for goods, kitchen utensils and cleaning products.
- ❖ Appraise staff performance and provide feedback to improve productivity.
- Recruiting, training and supervising staff.
- Maintaining the SASO records.
- ❖ Prepared a Quality manual according to SASO (Saudi Arabian Standards Organization) standards.
- Overseeing stock levels.
- ❖ Handling customer enquiries and complaints.
- ❖ Driving process improvement activities with the aim of hitting QA targets.
- Giving advice and support on a range of quality issues as required.
- ❖ Log sheets were implemented.
- ❖ Help launch new food court concept and culinary operations programs in conjunction with marketing division and culinary team.
- ❖ Control costs and expenditures through detailed analysis of appropriate purchasing and inventory.
- * Recruit hire train and mentor staff developing skills and customer service excellence.
- Supervised all staff and prepared daily work schedules.
- **!** Ensured that food was prepared in accordance with industry safety standards.
- ❖ Tracked weekly and monthly revenue and prepared quarterly financial reports.
- Evaluate employees and identify weaknesses.
- Identify training needs according to needs.
- ❖ Based on research, plan and implement training programs that will prepare employees for the next step of their career paths.
- Oversee employee attendance and performance.
- Track employee success and progress.
- Communicate all the training programs on a timely basis.
- ❖ Have a program announcement marketing strategy.
- Bring guest presenters if necessary.
- Prepare and present reports on training program.

- Maintain quality standers.
- Follow Baladey & SASO procedure.

Educations & Certificates:

- Master's Degree in Gastronomy
- ❖ Tunisin Hotel School Hammamt Diploma In Kitchen CAP 1987
- Tunisin Hotel School Hammamt Diploma In Kitchen BTH 1989
- ❖ Tunisin Higher Institute of Tourism Diploma In Kitchen BTS 1991
- Consultant Master Battle Chef Arabia
- WAMC Branded Representative Chef
- World Association Master Chef Consultant
- Culinary International Judge
- Master In International Cuisine
- Food Safety & Pest Control
- Food Safety (Personal, Food & General Hygiene)

Pro Skills:

- Exhibition & Conferences.
- Designing.
- ❖ Welcome Speech.
- Documents Arrange.



Thank You For Reviewing My Resume..